Guide to the Student Newspapers Collection Student newspaper publications of the Danbury Normal School, Danbury Teachers College, Danbury State Teachers College, Western Connecticut State College and Western Connecticut State University RG 5.15.1
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Inventory, 42054
  - Dee N Ess, October 1931 through May 1936, 1931-1936; 42093 (Box 1)
    February 23, 1936, Vol. 12, No. 18 Club News; Augusta Sutton lectures on the Constitution; DNS students Doris Baxter and Margaret Stone were guest speakers at the New Haven Normal School; DNS faculty member, Grant E. Finch, speaks to Universalist Men's Club on the true story of John Wilkes Booth; poem "Washington" by Nancy Byrd Turner; "Rules of Civility" from George Washington's Copybook; profile of Miss Tobias and Mr. Brill; Club and Assembly Notes and Personals.
    March 4, 1936, Vol. 12, No. 19 Editorial Board listed; DNS girls visit Camp Fechner on 2/18/1936; Coming Events; Editorial on crime prevention; Book review on "Silas Crockett" by Mary Ellen Chase; Club Notes; Poetry by alumnae Margaret M. Worthy and Ruth Miller; Personals; Alumnae Notes; Assembly Notes for 2/20 and 3/2.
    April (Undated) Thirty students from DNS attend Eastern States Conference in New York City by May Sherwood; Augusta Sutton attends Conference on Better Personnel in Education held at the Edgewood School in Greenwich; Club and Assembly Notes; Personals; "Normal School vs. College" by Eleanor Kingman.
    April (Undated) Club and Assembly Notes; Alumnae Notes; profile of Rachel Field, author of children's books and plays.
    April (Undated) Delegates attend Country Life Conference; Mrs. deVillafranca addressed the Ridgefield PTA on "The Value of Music in the Public Schools;" Toscanini farewell concert in Carnegie Hall; Personals; Alumnae, Assembly and Club Notes; Profile of Robert Frost.
    May 13, 1936, Vol. 12, No. 28 Alumnae Notes; Personals and Club Notes; Dramatic Club production of "Ladies in Waiting" by Cyril Campion; profile of Will Cather.
    May 13, 1936, Vol. 12, No. 28 (Final issue with year's activities) Editors for the years 1935-1936 and their assistants listed; Foreword by Ralph C. Jenkins; Science Club marks nature trail at Squantz Pond; Coming Events; poetry by Ella Quitt '39; Summary of events by the Athletic Association, Craft Guild, Dramatic Club, The Forum, the Glee Club, Philomathean Club, Rural Club, and Science Club; Assembly events; book review on "Silas Crockett" by Mary Ellen Chase; Social Committee; Welfare Committee; "Who's Been Who;" and, the Junior's Last Will and Testament dated June 20, 1936.
  - Dee Tee Cee, September 1936 through October 1937, 1936-1937; 42092 (Box 1)
    Numbering Incorrect December 2, Vol 11, No. 11 - December 9, Vol. 11, No. 13
    Numbering Incorrect January, February, March, April, May Issues numbered incorrectly
    Biographical / Historical
    September 1936, Vol. 13, No. 2 Dee Tee Cee Editorial Staff listed; members of Athletic Association hike to Wildman's Landing at Lake Candlewood; Freshman receiption; Club Notes; Alumnae Notes; The Forum column by K. A. Sutton; faculty notes.
    September 1936, Vol. 13, No. 3 Ninety members of the Athletic Association enjoy hike to Wildman's Landing; Dramatic Club holds open meeting; Personals; The Poetry Corner: Poems by Adele Flanagan and Edward Thomas; Faculty Hobbies; Literary Notes on "Gone With The Wind" by Margaret Mitchell.
    October 1936, Vol. 13, No. 4 Rural Club visits schools and Marion Newton's farm; Danbury Fair begins; Club Notes; Letter to the Editor regarding time constraints on students; Poetry Corner: Poems by Theodore J. Shannon and Orrick Johns; Sophomores Inspect Wilton School; Personals; Faculty Hobbies.
    October 1936, Vol. 13, No. 5 Dee Tee Cee Editorial Staff listed; Athletic Association members hike to McKay's farm in Cedar Heights; Newly organized Men's Forum to present varied social program; Lord Marley, Vice Chairman of the House of Lords in the British Parliament will be guest speaker on December 11 at the Green Hotel; Tennis Tournament begins; Editorial on the expiration of Article xix of the Washington treaty of 1922 by Helen Pauloski; Literary Notes: "Around The World In Eleven Years" by the children of Mr. Abbe, a newspaper photographer and Mrs. Abbe, a former follies girl; Reviews of the newest plays on Broadway; Personals by Jessie Levino; Club News.
    October 28, 1936, Vol. 14, No. 6 Dee Tee Cee staff listed; Men's and Women's Forum news; Sports News; Class News; Alumnae News; Editorial on the religious education; Club news; Dramatic Club rehearsing for "Rector" and "Wedding Spells;" Personals; Poem "Reverie" and "To A Brook" by Martha Warner; New plays on Broadway.
    November 4, 1936, Vol. 15, No. 7 Dee Tee Cee Editorial Staff listed; The Forum Dinner; Dramatic Club's three act play "Wedding Spells" to be given on November 24th; Club activities and sports news; Personals; Poetry of New England; The Book Nook.
    November 11, 1936, Vol. 11, No. 8 Editorial Staff listed; Augusta Sutton addressed the Armistice Day meetings of the League of Women Voters; Book news and Reviews; poetry by Jane Reardon and Ralphine Patton; Club News and Personals.
    November 18, 1936, Vol. 11, No. 9 Club Notes, Personals; poetry by Harriet Lawlor, C. O., and M. P.; Cinema Briefs.
    November 25, 1936, Vol. 11, No. 10 Dee Tee Cee Editorial Staff listed; Club News; Opera News; Annual Visit to Town Farm; "On Broadway;" Personals, student poetry; and, Inquiring Photographer.
    December 2, Vol. 11, No. 11 Dee Tee Cee Editorial Staff listed; Men's baseketball; DNS faculty and students to air 15 minute musical program on WICC radio; International News; plays and pictures review; Children's Theater; Personals; student poetry.
    December 9, Vol. 11, No. 13 Assemby Notes; local events; Drama and Music Notes; poetry; Club News; December's Air Waves; local news.
    December 16, Vol 11, No. 14 The Forum Banquet; Assembly News; Personals; Club News.
    December 22, 1936, Vol 11, No. 15 Christmas program; Melody Singers visit DTC; Club News; Opera news; Poetry Corner; and, Humor Column.
    January 6, 1937, Vol 13, No. 15 Editorial Staff listed; Club News; Personals; "1936 In Review;" student poetry.
    January 13, 1937, Vol. 16, No. ? Music Centre to present The Mikado; Club News; Mr. Jenkins to speak in Assembly; "As We Begin 1937;" student poetry; Training School Notes, Personals; Faculty Hobbies.
    January 20, 1937, Vol. 13, No. 18 News story "Industry and Labor Again At Odds;" Opera news; Letter to the Editor regarding plan of study by A Progressive Junio; student poetry; men's basketball, Faculty Hobbies, and song hits of DTC.
    January 27, 1937, Vol. 14, No. 14 President Roosevelt's inauguration; Men's Forum to discuss Social Security Act; Men's basketball; Faculy replies to Progressive Junior's Letter to the Editor; short story and student poetry; Personals, Club News; Best Sellers; and Faculty Hobbies.
    February 1937, Vol 12, No. 19 Editorial Staff listed; Assembly and Club Notes; Winter formal; Personals; Locust Avenue Training School Notes; student poetry; book reviews.
    February 1937, Vol 12, No. 20 Club Notes; Musical Projects; student poetry on Abraham Lincoln; "The Shadow" column; Men's basketball; Inquiring Reporter; letters to St. Valentine.
    February 1937, Vol. 12, No. 21 A. A. Tea Dance; Assembly Notes; Club News; "The Shadow" column.
    March 3, 1937, Vol. 12, No. 22 Editorial Staff listed; the Nation and School News; Assembly and Club News; Carl Sandburg profiled; Personals and Etiquette columns; student poetry; book reviews on The Man Who Didn't Exist, Of Mice and Men, and "Paradise."
    [March 10, 1937], Vol. 12, No. 23 Editorial Staff listed; Metropolitan Opera news; "The Value of Alexander Bell's Invention;" Alumnae, Club and Assembly News, Personals; "Guess Who" column; student poetry by Nancy B. Turner, Henry Van Dyke; Hilda L. Frost; Modern Etiquette column; and "Where Is Our School Emblem?"
    [March 17, 1937], Vol. 12, No. 24 Prospective students; Mrs. deVillaFranca opinion on teaching music in school; publicity for progressive education; spelling bee; student poetry; book review "We Are Not Alone" by James Hilton; sports and club news; Personals; Phantom Three sees Sophmore B's in 1943.
    [March 24, 1937], Vol. 12, No. 25 Discussion on Danbury News-Times editorial comment on teacher training; Town Farm trip planned; Assembly News; student poetry and book reports on "Young Robert" by George Allen, and "A Lamp On The Plans" by Paul Horgan; Sports and Club News; Personals; and April events.
    No Date [March 31, 1937] Juniors conclude trial seminar plan; Progressive Education Association Meets; Club News; Welfare Committee presented musical progam at the Town Farm; student poetry; Easter Program; "Do You Remember When" column; and, Personals.
    No Date [April 15, 1937] Vol. 16, No. 28 Retaining Normal Schools or Teachers Colleges topic of discussion with lawmakers; Club News; "Madrigal" discussed; new Text Book Room; student poetry.
    No Date [April 22, 1937, Vol. 16, No. 29] Editorial Staff listed; Forum Column; Library Staff planning "Juvenile Collection;" Assembly News; "The New Finland;" Club News and Professional Scholarship; book review on "Cards On The Table" by Agatha Christie; Campus Chatter and Personals.
    No Date [April 28, 1937], Vol. 13, No. 20 Eastern States Conference; Assembly Notes; Club News; Of Mice and Men by John Steinback reviewed; Student poetry; Personals; Song Hits at DTC.
    No Date [May 5, 1937], Vol. 13, No. 21 Juniors to present "The Mystery of the Masked Girl;" Miss Emily Barnard, daughter of Dr. Henry Barnard to speak at DTC on May 10, 1937; Training School clases enterain in Assembly; Local News; Club Notes; Student Poetry.
    October 1937, Volume 1, Number 1 Danbury Normal becomes Danbury State Teachers College and Dr. Ralph C. Jenkins installed as President on September 29, 1937; Club and Alumnae News; Personals; Sports already organized at DTC; Forum Club Officers listed; first appearance of ads for local businesses.
    November 1937, Volume 1, Number 2 Augusta Sutton speaks at Armistice Day Service on November 7, 1937; Senior Class trips; The Pied Piper Puppeters from Cos Cob present "Little Red Horse;" Who's Who column; Club Notes; Literary Corner; Department News; Descriptive Ditties column; Campus Chatter; and, Alumnae News.
    December 1937, Volume 1, Number 3 History of Connecticut Club travels; Eighth Annual Forum Banquet, Dr. No Yong Park and Dr. Yutaka Minakuchi debate "The Far Eastern Crisis;" Assembly and Alumnae News; Sports; Training School Notes; and, Personals.
  - Dee Tee Cee, January 1938 through June 1938, 42091 (Box 4)
    No Subnote Content
    January 1938, Volume I, Number 4 DTC Men's basketball team photograph; Winter formal at DTC; Senior A's take trip to New York City; DTC wins opening basketball game; Titles conferred upon eight teachers; What do you think? column on international affairs; Club news; Assembly news; poetry by A. Coladarci, R. S. McDonald, Wilbur R. Turner, and Shelley; Alumnae News; DTC Personals, Training School Notes; Song hits of DTC.
    February 1938, Volume I, Number 5 Dr. Jenkins gives education views; College Night; State Progressive Education Association meeting to be held at Danbury High School; Freshmen Valentine party successful; Dr. Ralph C. Jenkins made member of National Education Association Committee on Supply, Preparation, and Certification of Teachers; Training School Notes; Sports and Clubs News; Alumni Notes; poetry by Ruth McDonald and A. Coladarci; Original poetry from Fifth Grade--Locust Avenue School; Popular Song Hits.
    March 1938, Volume I, Number 6 Sophomore Party has record attendance; Assemblies feature varied programs; Music Department to give annual concert; Basketball season closes for season; DTC Student 'Y' organizes for '38; Athletics at DTC article; Sport activities at DTC; What men and women will be wearing this spring; Club news; Poet's Corner; Training School Notes.
    April 1938, Volume I, Number 7 Foreign Affairs expert, Dr. James G.l McDonald, associate editor of the New YOrk Times, will speak in the college Assembly Hall; "Frosh" plan formal; faculty member addresses Americanization classes; Teachers College represented at Eastern States; Annual concert successful; college men to attend Athletic Conference; Seniors sponsor Play Day; Club News; Poet's Corner; Assembly news.
    June 1938, Volume I, Number 8 First Annual Commencement Exercises of Danbury Teachers College; Class of 1938 picture on front page; Commencement activities; seniors honored at formal by Juniors; Senior Poetry Corner; Senior Syllogisms; ClassWill; Henry Barnard Pageant celebrates Centennial; The Scholar's Dictionary; Class of 1938 History; Seniors Given Recognition.
  - Dee Tee Cee, November 1938 through May 1941, 1938-1941; 42090 (Box 2)
    November 1938, Volume II, Number 1 Dr. Alonzo P. Grace, State Commissioner of Education spoke to students and faculty on "The Changing School;" Danbury Players of DTC sponsor "Arms And the Man" by George Bernard Shaw; News Of The Clubs column; Campus Chatter; Clubs name officials; "Dressing for Class, What to wear and how to wear it."
    December 1938, Volume II, Number 2 Sir George Paish, noted British economist, to speak at Forum's annual banquet; Dr. Ralph C. Jenkins appoionted 1939 chairman of the New England Teachers Preparation Association; Sport News; Poetry by Theresa Walsh, Helen O'Grady, and Emmet W. Bongar; Club News; Campus Chatter; Dressing For Formals column.
    January 1939, Volume II, Number 3 Senior Class to give "Stage Door" as its senior play;Sport News; Book Review on "This Proud Heart" by Pearl S. Buck; Campus Chatter; poetry by Harry Carey, Arthur Coladarci, Mariette Keane, Helen Joyce and T. Walsh; Dressing For Sports; Senior visit New York's art museum.
    February 1939, Volume II, Number 4 Music Department to present Deems Taylor's arrangement of "The Highwayman" by Alfred Noyes; Senir formal successful; Book review of "Oscar Wilde, The Man, The Artist, The Martyr" by Boris Brasol; Sports News; Training School Notes; Campus Chatter; poetry by Jeanne Robb, Emmet W. Bongar; and Paul Coladarci; Dressing for Class
    April 1939, Volume II, Number 5 Freshmen to sponsor formal dance; Training Schools to present pageant dealing with the development of rhythms, songs and dance; Book Reviews on "Reaching for the Stars by Nora Waln, "My Son, My Son" by Howard Spring, and "The Summing Up" by W.Somerset Maugham; Club and Sports News; Seniors to present "Stage Door;" Campus Chatter; Poetry by Harry Carey, H.Starr Jackson, and Paul Coladarci; Dressing for Class; and, Faculty News.
    May 1939, Volulme II, Number 6 Activities scheduled for senior week; Junios sponsor formal for seniors; Student elections; Forum guest speaker Mrs. Miriam Beard Vaghts gives historical background for Hitler's rise to power; Campus Chatter; Club and Sports News; Book reviews on "My Sister Eileen" by Ruth McKenny, "With Malice Toward Some" by Margaret Halsey, and "Listen! The Wind" by Anne Morrow Lindbergh; Governor R. E. Baldwin to speak at commencement; Poetry by A.Coladarci, Emmet W. Bongar and H. Starr Jackson.
    June 1939, Volume II, Number 7 Junior Prom successful; Commencement to be held June 16, 1939; Training Schools pageant successful; Faculty Facts, poetry by Arthur Coladarci, Emmet W. Bongar, and Hariett Jackson; Campus Chatter; DTC BestSellers, "What's On Your Mind" column.
    October 1939, Volume III, Number 1 Faculty attend annal Convocation held at New Britain; Freshman reception; sophomore formal; Book Review on "All This and Heaven Too" by Rachel Field; Clubs organize at DTC; Campus Chatter; Faculty News.
    November 1939, Volume III, Number 2 Senior Class select "You Can't Take It With You" as their senior play; Danbury Players sponor play festival; Forum Luncheon successful; Fire Drill Committee organized; Sport News; Faculty Facts; Campus Chatter; Assemby Notes; poetry by Emmet Bonegar, Harriett Jackson, Kathryn Barrett, and Thomas Daly.
    December 1939, Volume III, Number III Senior Yearbook staff selected; Dr. Lengyel to be Forum Speaker; Senior Class Play column; Dr. Jenkins speaks on Henry Barnard; Book Review on "The Memoirs of Julian Hawthorne" by Edith Garrigues Hawthorne; Faculty Facts; Campus Chatter; Club and Dorm News; and, poetry by Arthur Coladarci.
    April 1940, Volume III, Number 7 Casting completed for Iolanthe; Freshman to sponsor formal; Club News; Sport News; Book Review on "A Novel of the Life of Galileo" by Zsolt de Harsanyi; Campus Chatter; Dorm News; Student poetry by Arthur Coladarci and Jeanne Robb.
    May 1940, Volume III Number 8 Junior Class signs Enoch Light and his orchestra for the Junior-Senior promenade in honor of the graduating class; Alumni hold reunion; Club News; Two students discuss war, Section 1; Assembly Notes; Campus Chatter; Dorm News; student poetry by Jeanne Robb and Arthur Coladaric; Alumnae News.
    June 1940, Volume III, Number 9 Light's Orchestra plays at Junior-Senior Prom; Seniors In Final Week, activities planned; Last words of the seniors; A. A. Activities; The Seniors in Poetry; Campus Chatter; Dorm Doings; Assembly News.
    Introductory Issue 1940, Vol. IV, No. 1 Freshman reception; Flying courses offered to college students with two years of college training; Sports Panorama Day successful; Enrollment increases; DSTC entering 37th academic year; Sports News; Club News; Asembly Notes; Campus Chatter; Dorm Doings.
    October 1940, Volume IV, Number 2 Senior B. World Literature Class visited the productions of "The Cricket on the Hearth' and "Twelfth Night" at the Chekhov Theatre in Ridgebury; First Aid Course Offered; Class of '44 holds first picnic; Flying courses underway; Campus Chatter; Dorm News; DSTC gives extension courses; Book reviews on "Portrait of Jennie" by Robert Nathan and "The Boy and Girl Tramps of America" by Thomas Minehan; Meteorite specialist spoke to Junion B division geology class; Club Activities; Sport News Column.
    November 1940, Volume IV, No. 3 Senior play "Death Takes a Holiday;" Forum dinner party speaker Dr. Frederick L. Schuman, Prof. of Political Science at Williams College; Red Cross First Aid Course; Sport News and Club News Columns; Book Review on "Mrs. Miniver" by Jan Struther; Forum Column; Student poetry by Sarah E. Smith, C. L. Cleaveland; and, Oliver Goldsmith; Campus Chatter and Dorm News; "Slanguage" versus American language heard on campus.
    December 1940, Vol. IV, No. 4 DSTC will present the Chekhov Theatre Company in "The Cricket On the Hearth;" Assembly Notes; Club and Sport News columns; student poetry by Emmet W. Bongar, William Young, Sarah E. Smith, Sarah Reed; and H. Starr Jackson; Campus Chatter; Club News; Forum News gives history and offspring of The Forum which was founded by Dr. Augusta Sutton.
    January 1941, Vol. IV, No. 5 "The Cricket On the Hearth" review; Publications Association formed; D.T.C. Basketball Squad, 1940-1941, labeled photograph; Athletic Association news; Assembly notes; Book Review on "You Can't Go Home Again" by Thomas Wolfe; Dorm and Club News; Campus Chatter; Forum News.
    February 1941, Vol. VI, No. 6 President Jenkins attends the Natiional Conference of Defense Committees of Colleges and Universities; Remedial courses organized; Editorial on need to organize an Athletic Association; Assembly Notes; Sports Column; Campus Chatter and Dorm Doings; student poetry by Alabert E. Bedat, Sarah Smith, Mary E. Walsh, Emmet W. Bongar, and Eugene McGowan; Students interest in driving course.
    March 1941, Vol. VI, No. 7 DTC to attend Eastern States Association for Teachers Convention; Alum Daniel Skandera, class of 1940, to get wings; DSTC will sponsor second annual Drama Day; Editorial on Student Council; Assembly and Faculty Notes; Club News focus on The Forum and its activities; Campus Chatter; New column "Advice to Lovelorn" debuts; student poetry; sport activities.
    April 1941, Vol. IV, No. 8 Miss Anna E. Scollin to be honored at a dinner party; Annual Forum Spring Lecture/Dinner to hear Mr. Joseph Barnes, foreign editor of the New York Post who will give analysis of current war; Club and Assembly News; Sport News; Campus Chatter and Dorm News; student poetry by Evelyne Rotunda, Mary E. Walsh and others; Faculty News.
    Senior Issue 1941, Vol. IV, No. 9 Graduation day program published; Yale Collegians to play at the annual Junior-Senior Prom; Senior activity week; June 4, 1941 Senior Class day Exercises; Reminiscing; Assembly Reviews; Faculty News; Campus Chatter; Athletic Association news.
  - Campus Crier, October 1941 through November 1942, 1941-1942; 42089 (Box 2)
    October 22, 1941, Volume I, No. 2 Club and Dorm News; Men's Mixer; Short biography of notable undergraduates quiz; Freshman news and elections; Faculty News; Athletic Association News; Clubs News; Indian Summer Formal October 24th.
    November 17, 1941, Volume I, Number 3 Forum members attends New England International Relations Conference at Smith College; Students attend New England Conference; Sophomore training; Student Council news; Men's basketball; touch football tournament; Faculty News; Forum members visit Federal Correctional Institute to participate in newly installed "Prison Forum."
    December 18, 1941, Volume. I, Number 4 No deferments for college students; Freshmen news; Assembly news; Senior activities; DTC Seniors present "What A Life" in the Danbury High School Auditorium; Sports news.
    November 1942, Volume I, Number 2 Dr. Grant E. Finch honored at convocation of the Connecticut State Board of Education; Seniors to present "The Man Who Came to Dinner" by Hart and Kaufman; field trips; Victor Hasler, Sophomore Class President, drafted; Editorial addressed to faculty on "cuts;" Student officers and committee members listed; "Men in Service--More About The Boys In Camp;" Club News and activities.
    October 8, 1941, Volume I, No. 1
    Spring Semester 1942
    October 1942, Volume I, Number 1
  - The Inkling, March 1944 through June 1947, 1944-1947; 56489 (Box 2, Folder 7A - 14)
    March 1944, Volume 1, Number 1
    Editorial: The Neonate; DTC sponors Danbury Citizens' Forum; A Word From: The Freshmen, The Juniors, The Seniors, and Council; Club News; Forum News.
    April 1944, Volume 1, Number 2 Youth Confernece in May; Editorial "Pros and Cons;" Student Council News; Press Committee news; "cut system" a debatable subject.
    May 1944, Volume 1, Number 3 Pageant "Our Latin American Neighbors" to be held in June; Editorial "Girl Wanted" discussing pros and cons of working versus education; Notes From column; Yearbook near completion.
    June 1944, Volume 1, Number 4 Wartime Changes In College Program, Acceleration-Deceleration Cycle; Senior Class picture; Summer activities, Kappa Delta Pi news, "Much Ado About the Pageant" column; School Calendar; poem The Day Shall Come" by Ruth F. Carlson; Senior Scoops column.
    November 1944, Volume II, Number 1 Dr. Leslie Pinckney Hill, of the Cheney Teachers Training School, visits campus; Evolution and Revolution--The Inside Story of Council [The Council of the Cooperative Government Association]; Who's Who [clubs officials]; Dr. Grant E. Finch Retires; New Faculty; Forum attends New Britain Conference.
    December 1944, Number II, No. 2 Class of '45 Graduates, Shakespearian Play "Comedy of Errors" presented by Junior Class; Editorial on Educational Opportunities; Letters to the Editor; Kappa Delta Pi solumn; Our Post-War Plans column; Junior Commentaries; Assembly Bulletin; Eastern States Conference.